Andre Uzamurengera

KG 565 ST, Kigali Skype:**Uzamurengera** uzandre12@gmail.com

A data science and software engineer with over 10 years of experience delivering IT solutions to complex challenges. Over the past 4 years, analyzed data from financial institutions at Central Bank of Rwanda to monitor financial risk and support the stability of Rwanda's financial sector. Trained more than 1,500 students at the University of Rwanda in programming and data analysis, and continue to focus on data science, software engineering, and computer networks as I advance in my career.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist in Bank Supervision

Jan 2022 - present

National Bank of Rwanda

- Cleaning Data identifying, assessing, and resolving any data quality issues, developing, and executing data cleanup measures.
- Extracting, manipulating, and exploring data using quantitative, statistical, and visualization tools.
- Building algorithms, predictive models, and dashboards that get deployed in the form of products, policy, or scientific research.

Assistant lecturer in Computer Science

2015 - 2022

University of Rwanda

- Developing and teaching modules of computer science
- Working with the faculty to deliver lectures and making sure that students understand the concepts taught
- Enhancing programming and networking skills of more than 1000 students in the University of Rwanda

Software Engineer (Practicum Project)

Jan 2019 - May 2019

Rwanda Information Society Authority (RISA)

- Developed an Android application for the Government Command Center commonly known as GCC.
- Analyzed the GCC database structure and redesigned a proper database that could solve the identified issues.
- Recommended the RISA team on want could be done to fix all other issues in the GCC.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

2018 - 2020

Carnegie Mellon University

- Preparing weekly recitations, assignments, labs, and quizzes along with solutions for the assignments
- Grading homework assignments, labs, quizzes and assigning grades before deadlines
- Holding office hours to help students grasp the concepts taught in class and answers their questions about the course

Software developer intern May 2018 – Aug 2018

RURA

- Developed the Integrated e-Ticketing System for all transport companies in Rwanda
- Analyzed data from transport companies and presented key information on a friendly dashboard that helps
 RURA to get insights about transport

EDUCATION

CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY AFRICA

2017 - 2019

Master of Science in Information Technology

Concentrations: Software Engineering, Telecommunication & Computer Networks

UNIVERSITY OF RWANDA IN PARTNERSHIP WITH ÖREBRO UNIVERSITY

2016 - 2018

Master of Science in Information systems

Concentrations: e-Government

NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF RWANDA

2010 - 2013

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Systems

Concentrations: Software Engineering & Networking

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Mobile applications development certified by the Kenya National Commission for UNESCO.
- Artificial Intelligence Analyst certified by IBM
- Programming languages: NodeJS, Java, Python, NativeScript, PHP, C/C++, JavaScript and MATLAB.
- Building Ethernet network using routers and switches certified by CISCO
- Took courses such as Fundamental of Software Development, Data Structure & Algorithms, Advanced Database Systems, Data Inference and AppliedMachine Learning, Data Analytics, Advanced Programming (Java), Software Defined Radio, Information Security, Vulnerability Assessment& Testing, Fundamental of Telecommunication Networks, Information System Evaluation etc.